The true story of a real fake.
Catch Me If You Can is a drama, crime film directed by Steven Spielberg.
A true story about Frank Abagnale Jr.
who, before his 19th birthday, successfully conned millions of dollars worth
of checks as a Pan Am pilot, doctor, and legal prosecutor.
An FBI agent makes it his mission to put him behind bars.
But Frank not only eludes capture, he revels in the pursuit.
Frank Abagnale Jr., played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Carl Hanratty, played by Tom Hanks.
Frank Abagnale, played by Christopher Walken.
Roger Strong, played by Martin Sheen.
Paula Abagnale, played by Nathalie Baye.
Brenda Strong, played by Amy Adams.
Catch Me If You Can is a 2002 American crime comedy-drama film directed and produced by Steven Spielberg and starring Leonardo DiCaprio
and Tom Hanks with Christopher Walken, Martin Sheen, Nathalie Baye, Amy Adams, and James Brolin in supporting roles.
The screenplay by Jeff Nathanson is based on the eponymous and  semi-autobiographical book by Frank Abagnale Jr., who claims that prior to his 19th birthday, he
successfully performed cons worth millions of dollars by posing as a Pan American World Airways pilot, a Georgia doctor, and a Louisiana parish prosecutor.
However, the truth of his story is, as of the 2020s,  heavily disputed.
A movie version of Abagnale's book was contemplated soon after it was published in 1980 but
began in earnest in 1997 when Spielberg's DreamWorks bought the film rights.
David Fincher, Gore Verbinski, Lasse Hallström, Miloš Forman, and Cameron Crowe were all
considered to direct the film before Spielberg decided to direct it himself.
Filming took place from February to May 2002.
The film opened on December 25, 2002, to major critical and
commercial success, grossing $352 million worldwide.
At the 75th Academy Awards, Christopher Walken and John Williams were nominated
for Best Supporting Actor and Best Original Score, respectively.
The film explores themes of fbi, con man,
biography, based on true story, con artist.
The tone is emotional.